Guide to the World Fairs & International Expositions sheet music collection, 1851-1974 M2221
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
World Fairs & International Expositions sheet music collection
1851-1974
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
M2221
1.5 Linear Feet (2 flat boxes and 1 map folder)
Content Description
Sheet music relating to World Fairs and Expositions from 1851 - 1984, 131 sheets. There is a detailed catalog provided from the dealer
Biographical / Historical
World's fairs and world expositions have been held since 1851, when The Great Exhibition opened in London. Such expositions are generally large international expositions lasting for 3-6 months, and are designed to showcase different nations' achievements.
Scope and Contents
A collection of 131 original pieces of published sheet music celebrating or commemorating specific world's fairs in America and Europe from 1851-1984. Cities represented include Paris, New Orleans, London, New York, and more. Especially represented in the collection are the 1893 Chicago fair, 1904 St. Louis fair, and 1915 and 1939 San Francisco fairs.
Arrangement
Arranged by fair/exposition.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase; 2017. Accession MSS 2017-134.
Trade shows -- United States; Trade shows -- Europe; Marc Selvaggio, Bookseller ABAA
- 1851 London - The Great Exhibition
  - Labitzky: The Exhibition Quadrille, 1851 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1)
- 1853 New York - Exhibition of the Industry of All Nations
  - Byerly, William: The Crystal Schottisch, 1853 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1)
- 1876 Philadelphia fair - Centennial Exposition
  - Whittier, John G. and John K. Paine: Centennial Hymm, 1876 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mack, E.: The Centennial March, 1876 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1)
- 1878 Paris fair - Exposition Universelle
  - Carre, Emile and Victor Robillard: Vite au Trocadero, 1878 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2)
- 1884 St. Louis fair - St. Louis Exposition
  - Werner, Henry: Exposition March, 1884 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2)
- 1885 New Orleans fair - World Cotton Centennial
  - Cox, Clifford: New Orleans Exposition Grand March, 1885 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2)
- 1889 Paris fair - Exposition Universelle
  - Soulacroix, Jacques: Valse Exposition, 1889 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Delormel and Garnier; R. Stretti: Je Viens Voir L'Exposition, 1889 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2)
  - Esse, Rene (words): Les Saints a l'Exposition, 1889 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fiorentino, G.: Le Pays des Fes. Souvenir de L'Exposition, 1889 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
- 1893 Chicago fair - World's Columbian Exposition
  - Schleiffarth, George: Shoninger Grand March, 1893 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Brainard, S.: Samples of Latest Music. Try them on your piano, 1893 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carpenter, Andrew G.: World's Fair Grand March, 1893 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lamb, Arthur J. and Harry F. Carson: The Midway Grenadiers, 1893 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lampard, G. R.: Columbian Exposition March, 1893 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Markstein, S.: World's Fair March, 1893 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Maywood, George: World's Exposition March, 1893 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Rankin, Edward F. and Harry Earl: The Morrissey Grenadiers, 1893 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ricci, Signor Guglierlmo: Cairo Street Waltz, 1893 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5)
- 1894 San Francisco fair - California Midwinter International Exposition
  - Hyer, Alma E.: Midwinter Fair Waltz, 1894 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hutchinson, Al H. and George J. Southwick: Our Great Midwinter Fair, 1894 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5)
- 1895 Atlanta fair - Cotton States and International Exposition
  - Sousa, John Philip: King Cotton March, 1895 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lamb, Arthur J. (words) and G [iuseppe] Valisi (music): The Southern Beauty, 1895 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6)
- 1897 Nashville fair - Tennessee Centennial and International Exposition
  - Bernhardt, Maurice: Tennessee Centennial Prize March, 1897 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6)
- 1900 Paris fair - Exposition Universelle
  - Valisi, G.: Marche du Nouveau, 1900 (Flat-box 1, Folder 8)
  - La Marche Russe du Pont Alexandre et a Marche de la Garde Francaise. Pour piano a deux mains, 1900 (Flat-box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mayer, P.: Marche Celebre d la Porte Monumentale, 1900 (Flat-box 1, Folder 7)
  - Merot, Jules: Marche de 1900 (Flat-box 1, Folder 7)
  - Valisi, G.: Les Merveilles de l'Exposition, 1900 (Flat-box 1, Folder 7)
- 1901 Buffalo fair - Pan-American Exposition
  - Arnold, Ion: Belle of Buffalo, 1901 (Flat-box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dillon Harry (words) and John Dillon (music): At the Pan-I-Marry-Can, 1901 (Flat-box 1, Folder 8)
  - Kleinbeck, B. Eliza's Trip to the Pan-American, 1901 (Flat-box 1, Folder 8)
  - Line, Hans S.: Pan-American Exposition March and Two-Step, 1901 (Flat-box 1, Folder 10)
- 1904 St. Louis fair - Louisiana Purchase Exposition
  - Zarn, G.G.: Strolling on the Pike, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 14)
  - Aronson, Rudolph: Down the Pike. Marche Cosmopoltaine, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 10)
  - Barney and Seymore [psudonym], 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 10)
  - Becucci, E.: The Pike. Polka, Two-step, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 11)
  - Blake, C.: The MIssouri Mule March (no kick coming), 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 11)
  - Davis, Dr. C.L.: St. Louis World's Fair Military March & Two-Step, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 11)
  - della Rovere, M.: Salute to St. Louis, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fassett, Raphel: Up and Down the Pike, March Two-step, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 12)
  - Feist, Felix F. and Harry Bennett: Strolling 'Long the Pike, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 12)
  - Joplin, Scott: The Cascades, a Rag, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lamb, Arthur J. (words0 ad G[iuseppe] Valisi (music): Southern Beauty, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 12)
  - Marks, Hugo O.: International Buck Dance, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 13)
  - Moret, Neil [pseudo. Charles N. Daniels]: A Deed of the Pen. March, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 13)
  - Poepping, Noel: Souvenir Pageant March, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 13)
  - Renucci, R.: Liberal Arts Souvenir March, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ryder, Fred L.: St. Louis Exposition, March and Two-step, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sterling, Andrew B. and Kerry Mills: Meet Me in St. Louis, Louis, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 14)
  - Turpin, Tom: The St. Louis Rag, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 14)
  - Wagner, Carl: Gund's Peerles March, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 14)
- 1905 Portland fair - Lewis and Clark Centennial Exposition
  - Burnett, Jack: On the Portland Trail, 1905 (Flat-box 1, Folder 15)
  - Decker and Verguth: Bailey Gatzert March, 1905 (Flat-box 1, Folder 15)
  - Haywood, Nat: When We Get on the Trail, 1905 (Flat-box 1, Folder 15)
  - Hobile, A.S.: Lewis and Clark Centennial Exposition March, 1905 (Flat-box 1, Folder 15)
  - Marshall, Micaiah: Put Me Off at Portland Oregon, 1905 (Flat-box 1, Folder 16)
  - McKee, Carrie: Sacajawea's Papoose Waltz, 1905 (Flat-box 1, Folder 16)
- 1906 Milan fair - Milan International/L'Esposizione Internazionale del Sempione
  - Ranfagni, Enrico: Byrrh Marcia, 1906 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
- 1907 Jamestown fair - Jamestown Exposition
  - Currley, Leo and James B. Mullen: Take me Down to Jamestown, Jimmie, 1907 (Flat-box 1, Folder 16)
  - Harig, Karl G. and Sidney D. Mitchell: Jamestown, Waltz Song and Chorus, 1907 (Flat-box 1, Folder 16)
  - Lyon, Jack an Claude Elam: Meet Me on the War Path at the Jamestown Fair, 1907 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Simmons, Samuel E.: Jamestown Expositio March, 1907 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Whiddit, Wm Wall: March of the Pohatan, 1907 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1)
- 1909 Hudson-Fulton fair - Hudson-Fulton Celebration
  - Marvin, Leon: Hudson-Fulton Celebration, 1909 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1)
- 1909 Seattle fair - Alaska–Yukon–Pacific Exposition
  - Heyman, Reba L.: The Greater Seattle March and Two Step, 1909 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Innes, Frederick Neil: Glora Washington. Two-step, 1909 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
- 1911 Rome fair - International Exhibition of Art/Esposizione internazionale d'arte
  - Buonomo, James: Marcia l'Esposizione di Roma, 1911 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
- 1911 Turin fair - Turin International/Esposizione internazionale dell'industria e del lavoro
  - Burgmein, [Giulio]: Valzer dell'Esposizione di Torino, 1911 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
- 1915 San Francisco fair - Panama–Pacific International Exposition
  - Bradley, Charles (words) and W. Stephens (music). Romanoff Caviar, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
  - Burke, J.E.: I Will Meet You at the Fair, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
  - Carter, Sidney and Charles N. Daniels, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
  - Casey, James W.: That's How They Spent Their Honeymoon, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cornwell, Wm. E.: In 'Frisco for the Fair, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
  - Dent, Vernon and George Oscar Young: 1915 Rag (Flat-box 2, Folder 4)
  - Don, Arthur and Jack McClellan: Frisco, You're a Bear, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4)
  - Everson, Louis W.: Selma, the Home of the Peach, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fagan, Harry R. and James Fagan: Frisco Town, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 8)
  - Fentress, Will A.: Meet Me in Frisco and We'll Go Out to the Fair, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4)
  - Friedman, Leo: Exposition March, San Francisco 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5)
  - Gallur, Damasus G.: San Francisco - Panama - 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5)
  - Gillespie, John and Armand Putz: Welcome to California, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5)
  - Graves, Andy (lyrics) and Eddie Jewell (music): San Francisco, The World's Fair Town (the city by the Golden Gate), 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5)
  - Standish, Joseph W. and Frederick V. Bowers: At the 1915 Fair (Flat-box 2, Folder 6)
  - King, Laura Schick: At the Panama Pacific Fair, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 6)
  - Langlin, C.H.: At the Panama Exposition, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 6)
  - Lewis, Sam M. and George M. Meyer: San Francisco (at the San-Fran-Pan-American Fair), 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 6)
  - Marrack, G. Forbes: The King of Air, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7)
  - Mayne, Lyne: That '15 Frisco Fair, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7)
  - McKenna, William J.: I'm Going Back to Frisco Town, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7)
  - Nordman, M. Ernestine: Fair Exposition Land, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 8)
  - Powers, Sam: Frisco Bound, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7)
  - Vogt, Theodor: Sculptors' Tango, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 8)
- 1924 Wembley fair - British Empire Exhibition
  - Oswald, Albert H.: Under the Empire Flag. Descriptive Fantasia on the Great Wembley Exhibition, 1924 (Flat-box 2, Folder 8)
- 1926 Philadelphia fair - Sesquicentennial Exposition
  - Hager, Fred: My Own LIberty Bell, 1926 (Flat-box 2, Folder 9)
- 1928 Long Beach fair - Pacific Southwest Exposition
  - Scaueer, Harry E. and Hal Mors: Song of Long Beach, 1928 (Flat-box 2, Folder 9)
- 1931 Paris fair - Paris Colonial Exhibition/Exposition coloniale internationale
  - Madison, Maury (words and music): Cherokee, 1931 (Flat-box 2, Folder 9)
  - Koger, Geo and Vicent Scotto and Leon Raiter. Viens a l'Exposition (or Viens a l"Ex...!), 1931 (Flat-box 2, Folder 9)
- 1933-1934 Chicago fair - Century of Progress International Exposition
  - Gaw, Col. George D.: Greetings, Chicago Welcomes you, 1933 (Flat-box 2, Folder 10)
  - Gerbig, Fred and Joe Hunt: Just a Little Cabin in the Hills, 1933 (Flat-box 2, Folder 10)
  - Kallen, Charles and Ernie Kratzinger: The Forest of Love and Romance, 1933 (Flat-box 2, Folder 10)
  - Sissle, Nobel (words) and Will H. Vodery music): O, Let Us Sing a New Song, 1933 (Flat-box 2, Folder 10)
  - Sousa, John Philip: A Century of Progress March, 1933 (Flat-box 2, Folder 10)
  - Barnouw, Erik and Billy Frisch: Rain or Shine (In a Fisher Body), 1934 (Flat-box 2, Folder 11)
- 1935 San Diego fair - California Pacific International Exposition
  - Smithson, Louis T. and H. Joseph Marshall: San Diego Fair, 1935 (Flat-box 2, Folder 11)
  - Pollay, F. Gilbert: "We;re Taking in" the San Diego Fair, 1935 (Flat-box 2, Folder 11)
- 1936 Dallas fair - Texas Centennial Exposition
  - Spencer, Glenn: Blue Bonnet Girl, 1936 (Flat-box 2, Folder 11)
- 1937 Cleveland fair - Great Lakes Exposition
  - Rose, Billy and Stanley Adams, and Belle Fenstock: Strangers in the Dark, 1937 (Flat-box 2, Folder 12)
- 1937 Dallas fair - Greater Texas & Pan-American Exposition
  - Kahal, Irving (lyric) and Sammy Fain (music): Don't You Know or Don't You Care, 1937 (Flat-box 2, Folder 12)
- 1937 Paris fair - Exposition Internationale des Arts et Techniques dans la Vie Moderne
  - Stervel (words) and Paul Gramon (music): A l'Expo a l'Exposition. Poster/broadsheet with a map of the Exposition grounds and a collection of 10 songs; Paris, 1937 (Map-folder 3)
  - Salzedo, F. and Totis and Herazal, 1937 (Flat-box 2, Folder 12)
  - Geogius and Gaston Claret: Le Chanson de l'Exposition, 1937 (Flat-box 2, Folder 12)
- 1939 New York fair - New York World's Fair
  - Rose, Bill and Ted Fetter and Dana Suesse: Yours for a Song, 1939 (Flat-box 2, Folder 13)
  - La Barre, Eugene: For Pea and Freedom. The Official Song of the World's Fair of 1940 in New York, 1939 (Flat-box 2, Folder 13)
  - Koehler, Ted and Rube Bloom: Don't Worry 'Bout Me. Cotton Club Parade, 1939 (Flat-box 2, Folder 12)
- 1939 San Francisco fair - Golden Gate International Exposition
  - Ballaseyus, Virginia: Mother Goose on Parade, 1939 (Flat-box 2, Folder 13)
  - Chapman, J. B. and Harry A. Powell: A Song of the Coastlands and Come on America to Treausre Island, 1939 (Flat-box 2, Folder 13)
  - Goldman, Edwin Franko: Golden Gate March, 1939 (Flat-box 2, Folder 14)
  - Meany, Ray and Bernie Kaai: Treasure Island March, 1939 (Flat-box 2, Folder 14)
  - Openhafer, E.F. (words) and Karl Stiska (music): Treausre Island March, 1939 (Flat-box 2, Folder 14)
  - Phelps, Philip: Let's Go to San Francisco. Dedicated to the Golden Gate International Exposition, 1939 (Flat-box 2, Folder 14)
  - Pollay, F. Gilbert: At the San Francisco Fair, 1939 (Flat-box 2, Folder 14)
  - Rose, Billy and Ted Fetter and Dana Suesse: Yours for a Song, 1939 (Flat-box 2, Folder 15)
  - Schaackey, Pauline: Welcome to Treasure Island, 1939 (Flat-box 2, Folder 15)
  - Tregina, A.: The Marine's Hymn, 1939 (Flat-box 2, Folder 15)
  - Westenberg, Mel: When the Sun Goes Down on Treasure Island, 1939 (Flat-box 2, Folder 15)
- 1962 Seattle fair - Century 21 Exposition
  - Twain, Georgette: C U at the Great Seattle Fair, 1962 (Flat-box 2, Folder 16)
- 1964 New York World's Fair
  - Sherman, Richard M. ad Robert B. Sherman: It's a Small World, 1964 (Flat-box 2, Folder 16)
  - Rivaux, Clause and Isi Dethier: March of the Belgian Village at the New-York World's Fair 1964-65 (Flat-box 2, Folder 16)
- 1974 Spokane fair - Expo '74
  - Grief, Jean Anthony: Meet Me by the River, at Expo Seventy-Four, 1971 (Flat-box 2, Folder 16)